"Eniwa Shii"
Hello?
もしもし？
たす… けて
...lp... me...
Huh?
えっ
Help me...
助けて！
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
The cat trail...
ネコ道…
On the cat trail...
I fell into the river...
ネコ道で… 川に落ちて…
It's so cold... I can't get out...
冷たくって… 出られない
あと少し頑張れ
Hang in there just a little longer.
スーパーカブが必ず助けにいく
My Super Cub is coming to the rescue.
Koguma-san...
小熊さん…
Are you okay?
大丈夫？
生きてる？
You alive?
起きて
Wake up.
Koguma-san, you really did
come and save me...
やっぱり… 小熊さんが…
助けにきてくれた…
I'm cold...
寒い
I can't climb out of here
while carrying you.
あなたを抱えてここを登ることはできない
手を貸すから　自分で這い上がって
I'll help, but you'll need
to pull yourself up.
Mm-hmm...
うん…
F-Forgive me...
す… すみません…
You're still lighter than my Cub, I think.
カブよりは軽い… かな
Um, are the police or an
ambulance coming...?
あの…
警察とか… 救急車は…
I didn't call them.
呼んでない
うちが近いから　風呂に入って着替えていくといい
I live close by, so you should take
a hot bath and change your clothes.
それから家まで送る
After that, I'll take you home.
What's up?
なに？
えっ！椎ちゃんが!?
Huh?! How's Shii-chan? Is she okay?
無事なの？
She's all right.
大丈夫
うん… そう…
Mm-hmm. Yeah. See to it, okay?
あとよろしく
消防レスキューは必要ないけど
You don't need fire and rescue, but I did
call someone driving the same color.
色が似ているのを呼んでおいた
Huh?
Um, what are you...?
あの… これは…
Koguma-san, you wouldn't...
小熊さん… まさか
You weigh less than a full stack of
the morning edition being delivered.
新聞配達のタケノコ積みの朝刊よりは軽い
Here we go.
行くよ
い～や～っ！
初めての小さな旅路
目的地ならいらないよ
何もない私の頬に
手招きするように風が吹く
寄り道　回り道
いつもの景色も鮮やかに
右手をひねるたび　何度でも胸が弾むから
さあ　ギアを上げて　顔を上げて
どこまでも伸びてく道だって
昨日より少し遠くまで
きみとなら怖くない　どこだって
私ひとりでは　作れない風だ
Wait just a minute.
ちょっと待ってて
Get undressed.
脱いで
Oh, forgive me--
あ… すみません
It's okay.
いいから
I'm going to wash your clothes.
服は洗濯しておく
All I have is that shampoo and body soap.
シャンプーとボディーソープはそれしかないから
あの… ありがとう… ございます
Um, thank you... very much.
You can thank the Cub.
礼ならカブに言って
This came out fine.
こっちは無事だった
But...
けど…
She wants to be like the two of you.
お二人に憧れてるんですよ
私たちに？
Like us?
Yes.
えぇ
買い物以外にもよく自転車に乗って　いろいろ回ってるみたいで
She seems to be riding
her bicycle around a lot more,
even when she's not shopping.
Almost as if she's trying
to catch up to you two.
まるで　お二人のあとを追いかけてるみたいに
私に押しつけられて乗っていたアレックス・モールトンですが
I'm the one who pushed the
Alex Moulton she's riding on her,
やっと好きになってくれたようで
and now that she finally seems
to have taken a liking to it,
なんだか　うれしいです
I kind of feel happy about it.
"A Distant Spring"
"Super Cub Episode 11"
小熊さん
Koguma-san...
U-Um...
あ… あのぅ
お風呂あいた？
Is the bath available?
礼子ちゃん!?
Reiko-chan?
Bath time, bath time!
お風呂！お風呂！
あの…
Um...
That's okay! Don't worry about these!
いいです！これは大丈夫です！
You want to go home in wet panties?
濡れたパンツで帰るつもり？
自分で… やります
I'll do it myself...
This room is dry in the winter,
so they'll be dry by tomorrow morning.
この部屋冬は乾燥するから
明日の朝までには乾いてる
Okay.
はい！
あの！やっぱり何かお手伝いします！
Um, I really ought to
do something to help--
It's just about done already.
もうできるから
Okay, dig in.
さぁ　食べよう
Ah, that smells great.
いい匂い
Whoa, Reiko-chan!
ちょっ!? 礼子ちゃん!?
Oh, curry udon!
おぉ　カレーうどん！
Well, I'd only get my
clothes dirty, so I'll just--
だったら服汚れちゃうし　このま…
んっ？
They're maintenance coveralls;
they're supposed to get dirty.
整備用だし　それなら汚れてもいい
Oh!
Let's eat.
食べよう
いただきます
Thank you for this food.
Delicious!
おいしい
Oh, you have hard-boiled eggs!
ゆで卵あるじゃ～ん
Excuse me...
ちょっと
Well, after all, Shii-chan
needs her nutrition, right?
だって～椎ちゃん　栄養つけなきゃでしょ？
There, your topping.
はい　トッピング
あ　ありがとうございます
Th-Thank you very much.
You're very welcome!
どういたしまして
You have more than
enough nutrition, right?
栄養足りてるでしょ？
え～っ？
Huh? I think I've done
enough to earn this.
私も結構働いたと思うけど？
Here.
はい
Oh, I'll take care of this!
あっ　それは私がやります
Shii-chan...
椎ちゃん
Yes?
は～い
What is it?
なんですか？
Your Moulton... has had it.
あのモールトン　もうだめだから
冬なんて…
I just...
冬なんて嫌いです
I just hate winter.
Why does it have to be this cold?
なんでこんなに寒いんですか？
I'm begging you, Koguma-san...
please make it spring for me, right now.
お願いです　小熊さん
今すぐ私を春にしてください
Please save me again with your Super Cub.
また… スーパーカブで助けてください
Please take this cold, dark winter...
この冷たくて暗い冬を…
どこかに…
...and send it...
send it away somewhere...
どこかに消してください！
I'm begging you...
お願いします…
お願いします！
I'm begging...
お願い…
That's...
カブに…
...not something my Cub... can do.
そんなことは… できない
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございました
Thank you so very, very much.
本当に　本当にありがとうございます
あ… いえ…
Oh, that's okay.
Here, a one-year free pass for our coffee.
これ　コーヒーの年間無料パスです
Both of you, please use it
as much as you like.
2 人でいっぱい使ってください
Th-Thank you very much.
あ… ありがとうございます
Does that mean we can drink coffee
here for free for a year?
これって　コーヒー 1 年タダってこと？
--Yes.
--Oh, yeah?
はい
Dear, sandwiches, too.
あなた　サンドイッチも
あぁ　そうだな
Ah, of course. Can I have that back?
ちょっといいかな
"All bread items free"
There. All sandwiches
and bread items are free.
はい
サンドイッチもパンも　全品無料です
Whoo!
Can we start using it today?
今日から使えたりします？
Of course!
もちろん
やった～！
Hooray! What am I going to get?
どれにしようかな～
Just as the frigid air that blankets
the town of Hokuto...
北杜の町を覆う　寒々しい空と
...and the chill winds of the
Southern Alps remain unyielding,
南アルプスの冷たい風が変わらないように
our uneventful days picked up
again the next day,
翌日から　代わり映えしない平穏な日々が続いた
and showed no signs of changing.
Good morning!
おはようございま～す
--Good morning.
おはよう
There was an old granny bike that
no one at her home rode anymore.
彼女の家で　誰も乗らないまま放置されていたママチャリ
This city cycle, with wheels larger
than her Moulton road racer's,
小径ロードレーサーのモールトンよりホイールの大きい
シティーサイクルの自転車が　彼女に似合わない
was not a good fit for her.
We traveled along our usual roads--us on
our Cubs, and her on her granny bike.
いつもの道を私たちはカブで　彼女はママチャリで走る
Our days were spent just coming to school,
then going home again.
ただ学校に来て　帰るだけの日常
Our Cubs were outfitted
for the cold weather,
私たちのカブも　寒冷対策が整い
so we could deal with the winter cold
and the snow that sometimes fell.
冬の寒さや　ときどき降る雪には対処できるようになっていた
There weren't really
any other issues to solve,
特に改善すべき問題点も　買う物もない
nor anything else to buy.
There were no more
opponents for us to fight.
戦うべき相手は　もういない
The project to turn the eat-in space into
an Italian bar had been put on hold.
イートイン・スペースをイタリアンバールにする計画はひと休みとなっていた
I asked her when she would start it again,
いつ再開するのか彼女に聞いても
--and she just said, "In a little while,"
「もう少しあとで」と　曖昧に笑うだけだった
--Thank you very much!
--and she just said, "In a little while,"
ありがとうございました！
with a noncommittal smile.
The Kagoshima Weather Observatory's
yoshino cherry blossoms
鹿児島地方気象台の桜　ソメイヨシノが開花しました
have begun to bloom.
They have started nine days
earlier than the average,
平年より 9 日早く　昨年よりも 4 日遅いという…
but four days later than--
"2nd Year"
"Final Exam"
"English"
Final exams are over at last!
やっと期末試験も終わったわね
Vacation starts tomorrow.
Do you have any plans?
明日からお休みですね
何か予定とかあるんですか？
Not really.
別に
Reiko-chan, how about you?
礼子ちゃんは？
Nah. Well, ride my Cub, I guess.
さぁ
まっ　カブに乗るとか？
Excuse me...
すみませ～ん
Coming!
は～い！
Please take your time, okay?
ゆっくりしていってくださいね
Thank you for waiting.
お待たせしました～
Thank you for the coffee.
ごちそうさま～
Um...
あの…
Please come by again, okay?
また来てくださいね
--Mm-hmm.
--Of course.
うん
もちろん
I sure hope spring gets here soon.
早く春にならないかなぁ
Once spring is here, all the cherry
blossoms around will bloom.
春になったら　この辺りの桜がいっぱい咲くんですよね
They said on the news that
they're already out in Kagoshima.
鹿児島ではもう咲いたってニュースで言ってた
Want to go see?
見にいこうか
Huh?
えっ
Go see the cherry blossoms.
桜　見に
I don't see... how we could...
そんなこと　できるわけ…
Maybe we ought to go...
行ってみようかな
Huh?
えっ？
Go see the cherry blossoms.
桜　見に
Koguma-san, could I...?
小熊さん　私も
Could I go with you, too, please?
私も連れていってください！
彼女が私たちに憧れていると
I was told that she wanted to be like us,
and that she was trying to catch up to us.
私たちを追いかけていると聞いた
But I was the one who was chasing her.
でも　追いかけていたのは私のほうだ
彼女は覚えているんだろうか？
I wonder if she even remembers...
...how on that day, she passed me up.
あの日
私を追い越していったことを
And it wasn't just that one time.
あのときだけじゃない
She always looks forward to what's
ahead of her, and runs after it.
いつも自分の行き先を見つめ　走り続けている
To me, she's the girl...
そんな彼女は　私にとっても…
...who's responsible for
introducing me to my Cub,
私をカブと出会わせてくれた子と
and whom I met through my Cub.
カブを通じて出会えた子
Where I once had nothing
in my life, now...
何もなかった私の生活に　今は…
As it stands now, this winter
is killing the three of us.
このままだと　3 人とも冬に殺される
So... let's all three of us
escape from winter.
ならば　3 人で冬から逃げよう
Let's go and snatch spring on our Cubs.
カブで春をつかまえにいこう
すれ違う風　未来に溶けてく
近づいてくる　優しいエンジンの音
透明だった世界に　車輪で色を付けよう
ともに駆け抜けた道
誰にも描けない私の絵になる
遠くで春が呼ぶ　すぐそこかもしれない
できるだけたくさんの　思い出連れてこう
一緒に過ごす日々　見つけた彩りは決して
色褪せない
いつだってずっと　そばにいるよ
"Episode 12"
"Super Cub"
Episode 12: "Super Cub."
第 12 話　「スーパーカブ」